Guide to the Kenneth Willis Clark papers, 1924-1980 UA.29.02.0160
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Kenneth Willis Clark papers
1924-1980
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Clark, Kenneth Willis, 1898-
UA.29.02.0160
23 Linear Feet
Kenneth Willis Clark was a faculty member in the Divinity School at Duke University. The Kenneth W. Clark papers include materials from Kenneth Clark's time as a faculty member in the Divinity School. Topics covered include teaching and work on a translation of the biblical New Testament from Greek manuscripts.
Access Restrictions
Access restricted. In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records. Contact Research Services for more information.
Biographical / Historical
Kenneth Willis Clark was a faculty member in the Divinity School at Duke University.
Scope and Contents
The Kenneth W. Clark papers include materials from Kenneth Clark's time as a faculty member in the Divinity School. Topics covered include teaching and work on a translation of the biblical New Testament from Greek manuscripts.
Bible. N.T. -- Study and teaching; Bible -- Geography; Duke University. Divinity School -- Faculty; Duke University. Divinity School -- Students; Duke University. Divinity School -- History; Clark, Kenneth Willis, 1898-
- Correspondence, 1930-1955 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1956-1976; undated (Box 2)
- Divinity School: Concilium (Box 2)
- Divinity School: Correspondence with students, 1933-1974; undated (Box 2)
- Divinity School: Curriculum and Requirements, 1930s-1967 (Box 2)
- Divinity School: Departmental correspondence, 1947-1975 (Box 2)
- Divinity School: Graduate Faculty of Religion: Minutes, Incomplete, 1945-1976 (Box 2)
- Divinity School: History by K.W. Clark (Box 3)
- Divinity School: Lectures (Box 3)
- Divinity School: Memos, 1938-1975; undated (Box 3)
- Divinity School: Recommendations, 1933-1975 (Box 3)
  Conditions Governing Access
  FERPA restriction until 2027-2045.
- Divinity School: Scholarships and Financial Aid (Box 3)
- Divinity School: Supply Pastor's School (Box 3)
- Divinity School: Visitation: Northern Alabama Conference (Box 3)
- Divinity School: Visitation: Texas Conferences. (Box 3)
- Chapel Committee (Box 3)
- Commencement Bibles (Box 3)
- Duke Library: purchases and Manx Collection, 8 folders (Box 3)
- Duke University Church: (Box 3)
- Scripture, Prayers, Poems (Box 3)
- Sermons, 3 folders (Box 3)
- Teaching Materials (Box 4)
  Scope and Contents
  Rough chronological order
- Teaching Materials (Box 5)
- Teaching Materials (Box 6)
- Divinity School: Divinity School Seminars, 1948-1954 (Box 6)
- Divinity School: Divinity School Seminars, 1955-1968 (Box 7)
- Methodist Church: Western North Carolina Conference: Board of Ministerial Training and Qualifications, 1952-1963; 3 folders (Box 8)
- Methodist Church: Christian Workers Training Schools, 1935-1960s; 6 folders (Box 8)
- Chapin Library: First Folio Theft (Box 8)
- Commencement Programs, 2 folders (Box 8)
- Travel, 7 folders (Box 8)
- Passports, 'Visas, other documents for KWC and ADC. (Box 8)
- Miscellaneous calling cards, notes and invitations (Box 8)
- Biographical and bibliographical information (Box 8)
- Retirement scrapbook, 1967 (Box 8)
- Memorials to KWC, 1979-1980 (Box 8)
- Descriptive Catalog of Greek New Testament Manuscripts in America (Box 9)
  Correspondence with holders of MSS; with publisher; reviews; text.
- Microfilm Project, 1949-1950 (Box 9)
  Mt. Sinai and Jerusalem
- International Greek New Testament Project (IGNTP): Correspondence, to June 1965. (Box 9)
- International Greek New Testament Project (IGNTP): Correspondence, July 1965-1969 (Box 10)
- International Greek New Testament Project (IGNTP): Minutes, memos, 1948-1968; undated (Box 10)
- International Greek New Testament Project (IGNTP): Notes and collations (Box 10)
- International Greek New Testament Project (IGNTP): Rules for collators, other instructions (Box 10)
- Research: Articles (Box 11)
  arranged alphabetically with exception of articles used in volume of KWC's collected essays
- Research: Book reviews (Box 12)
- Research: Interpreters Bible articles (Box 12)
- Research: Eight American Praxapostoloi: Reviews and correspondence (Box 12)
- Research: Addresses and lectures (Box 12)
- General research topics and notes (Box 12)
- Research: Professional associations (Box 13)
- Research: Trips to Mt. Athos, 1951; 1963 (Box 13)
- Research: Trips to St. Paul Festival, 1951 (Box 13)
- Research: Palestine Archaeological Museum (Box 13)
- Research: Professional papers, 1949-1963; undated (Box 13)
- Photographs (Box 13)
- Book drafts (Box 14)
- Article drafts (Box 14)
- Textual criticism (Box 14)
- Book drafts (Box 15)
- Article drafts (Box 15)
- Textual criticism (Box 15)
- Printed matter (Box 16)
- artifacts (Box 16)
- Seminar registry (Box 16)
- Translation (Box 17)
- Travel brochures (Box 17)
- IGNT Project (Box 18)
- IGNT Project (Box 19)
- Greek New Testment manuscript catalog (Box 19)
- IGNT Project (Box 20)
- Greek New Testment manuscript catalog (Box 20)
- Diplomas and other certificates (Box 21)
- Class of 1924 photograph (Box 21)
- Greek newspaper and magazines, 1962-1963 (Box 21)
- University of Chicago promotional brochure and other club materials (Box 21)
- Clippings about KWC (Box 21)
- Peddie Schpol (NJ) materials, including prize-winning essay by KWC (Box 21)
- KWC school and family memorabilia and correspondence (Box 21)
- pictures and clippings related to Divinity School and KWC (Box 22)
- framed picture of two children (Box 22)
- "Flowers of the Holy Land" cards (Box 22)
- photographs, including of KWC's trip to Jerusalem, an archaeological dig, and cathedrals (Box 22)
- "Kariye (Chora)" by Celik Gulersay, book (Box 22)
- Oxford Bible Atlas, 1962 (Box 22)
- "Cappadoce", book, in French (Box 22)
- Turkey travel guides (Box 22)
- Rare Books pamphlet (Box 22)
- notes (Box 22)
- list of Greek Manuscripts in KWC collection (Box 22)
- slides (Box 22)
- other printed materials (Box 22)
- Slides (Box 23)
- photographs (Box 23)
- notes (Box 23)
- Address file (Box 23)
- scores for songs by KWC (Box 23)
- Divinity School memoranda, faculty committee minutes (Box 24)
- Divinity School Student Representative Assembly charter, records, and reports (Box 24)
- correspondence (Box 24)